<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>passwords on The Programmer&#39;s Chest</title>
        <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/en/tags/passwords/</link>
        <description>Recent content in passwords on The Programmer&#39;s Chest</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>es-ES</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 13:47:29 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        <image>
            <url>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/img/bio-photo-rss.png</url>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/en/tags/passwords/</link>
            <title>passwords on The Programmer&#39;s Chest</title>
            <width>144</width>
            <height>144</height>
        </image>
        <atom:link href="https://elbauldelprogramador.com/en/tags/passwords/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Creating and managing passwords intelligently</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/en/good-passwords/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 13:47:29 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/en/good-passwords/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;changelog&#34;&gt;CHANGELOG&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;07.27.2017: &lt;strong&gt;Added&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Passwords Evolved: Authentication Guidance for the Modern Era&lt;/em&gt; to useful links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently there has been a lot of noise in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/en/tags/security/&#34; title=&#34;posts about security&#34;&gt;security&lt;/a&gt; field with &lt;strong&gt;wannaCry&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;breach with more than 230M accounts stolen&lt;/strong&gt;. Today more than ever it is necessary to have &lt;em&gt;good habits creating passwords&lt;/em&gt; when creating new accounts in any new service you sign up. This post shows some good practices I&amp;rsquo;ve been using since I became more security conscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-good-passwords&#34;&gt;Create Good Passwords&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing is to create a &lt;em&gt;strong and random enough password&lt;/em&gt;. There are many websites and tools for this purpose, such as &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Steve Gibson&amp;rsquo;s page&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; or the built-in tool in &lt;strong&gt;LastPass&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, for every new account you create in any service make a long password containing characters, numbers and symbols (see LastPass generator). A good choice for the &lt;strong&gt;password length would be anything above 50 character&lt;/strong&gt;, below is an example of the tool integrated in &lt;strong&gt;LastPass&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not want to use &lt;strong&gt;LastPass&lt;/strong&gt; you can use &lt;strong&gt;Steve&amp;rsquo;s generator&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets see how much time would it take to &lt;strong&gt;crack this 50-length&lt;/strong&gt; randomly generated password: 8e8f6$AB9^YgOJ4x$JqHknK&lt;em&gt;FXp&lt;/em&gt;uru2qyU3KXydaK*lJncQrE:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and what does it says &lt;strong&gt;Steve&amp;rsquo;s version?&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;use-a-password-manager&#34;&gt;Use a password manager&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course using such passwords you &lt;strong&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t expect to memorize them&lt;/strong&gt;, and that is a sign of a strong and good password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to manage your passwords you should use a password manager, I am using LastPass as these guys have demonstrated they know how to store your passwords in a secure way. ( I am basing this opinion on Steve Gibson&amp;rsquo;s knowledge on security, here are some talks about it: &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;II&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you&amp;rsquo;re​ using LastPass to generate and store your passwords securely, there is an extra layer you could put on top of that: &lt;strong&gt;“use LastPass intelligently”&lt;/strong&gt;, as I explain in the next section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;best-practices-to-use-a-password--manager&#34;&gt;Best Practices To Use A Password  Manager&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far you have a password stored in your password manager that&amp;rsquo;s​ impossible to memorize, that&amp;rsquo;s what a password manager is for. But the possibility that someone attack you and get all your LastPass information still could exists. Let&amp;rsquo;s suppose &lt;strong&gt;someone stole&lt;/strong&gt; all your data in LastPass, and to put us in the worst case scenario, &lt;strong&gt;ALL THE STOLEN DATA IS decrypted&lt;/strong&gt;. Well, one way to solve that is to only store &lt;em&gt;part of the password&lt;/em&gt; in LastPass, let me explain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you generate your password, you store that randomly generated password in your LastPass vault, but In the service itself, let&amp;rsquo;s say your Google account you set your password to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;8e8f6$AB9^YgOJ4x$JqHknK&lt;em&gt;FXp&lt;/em&gt;uru2qyU3KXydaK*lJncQrE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;APASSWORDYOUCANMEMORIZE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That way, even if all your LastPass data is stolen, the thief wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to log in into your accounts, as &lt;strong&gt;they only know part of your password.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;hardering-online-presence&#34;&gt;Hardering online presence&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days more and more services offer a Two factor authentication option, you should enable it in all services you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tfa&#34;&gt;TFA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you enable TFA, the service will show your backup&amp;rsquo;s codes in the case you lose your phone or can&amp;rsquo;t generate a TFA code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;securing-your-tfa-backups&#34;&gt;Securing your TFA backup&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important that you save this backup&amp;rsquo;s codes, but In a secure place. The best thing would be to print it in paper and store them in a banks box. But for most of us stored them in a external HDD or print them would do the trick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it, In this days I think applying this tips and bests practices should have your password pretty secure, but &lt;strong&gt;remember, nothing is complete secure&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What tips do you use to secure your passwords? Let me know in the comments!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;useful-links&#34;&gt;Useful links&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Passwords Evolved: Authentication Guidance for the Modern Era&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
