<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Noticias on El Baúl del programador</title>
        <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/tags/noticias/index.xml</link>
        <description>Recent content in Noticias on El Baúl del programador</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>es-ES</language>
        <image>
            <url>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/img/bio-photo.png</url>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/tags/noticias/index.xml</link>
            <title>Blog Logo</title>
            <width>150</width>
            <height>150</height>
        </image>
        <atom:link href="https://elbauldelprogramador.com/tags/noticias/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Nueva Guía Gratuita: Learning JavaScriptMVC -- Free 14 Page Excerpt</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-gua-gratuita-learning-javascriptmvc-free-14-page-excerpt/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 11:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-gua-gratuita-learning-javascriptmvc-free-14-page-excerpt/</guid>
            <description>&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img on=&#34;tap:lightbox1&#34; role=&#34;button&#34; tabindex=&#34;0&#34; layout=&#34;responsive&#34; src=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/img/nueva-gua-gratuita-learning-javascriptmvc-free-14-page-excerpt.jpg&#34; title=&#34;{{ page.title }}&#34; alt=&#34;{{ page.title }}&#34; width=&#34;199px&#34; height=&#34;258px&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScriptMVC is a client-side, JavaScript framework that builds maintainable, error-free, lightweight applications as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it does not depend on server components, it can be combined with any web service interface and server-side language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Learning JavaScriptMVC&amp;rdquo; will guide you through all the framework aspects and show you how to build small- to mid-size well-structured and documented client-side applications you will love to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book starts from JavaScriptMVC installation and all its components are explained with practical examples. It finishes with an example of building a web application. You will learn what the JavaScriptMVC framework is, how to install it, and how to use it efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book will guide you on how to build a sample application from scratch, test its codebase using unit testing, as well as test the whole application using functional testing, document it, and deploy the same. After reading Learning JavaScriptMVC you will learn how to install the framework and create a well-structured, documented and maintainable client-side application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Packt Enterprise books can be summed up through the tagline &amp;ldquo;Professional Expertise Distilled&amp;rdquo;. They take in-the-trenches knowledge from experienced software professionals, and distil it into a single, easy to follow manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;button-post&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bashyc-blogspot.tradepub.com/c/pubRD.mpl?sr=oc&amp;_t=oc:&amp;qf=w_pack39&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Descárgala&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visita la página &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/manuales-gratuitos/&#34;&gt;Manuales gratuitos&lt;/a&gt; o consulta el &lt;a href=&#34;http://elbauldelprogramador.tradepub.com/category/information-technology/1207/&#34; title=&#34;Catálogo completo de Guías gratuítas &#34;&gt;catálogo completo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
