<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>libros on El Baúl del programador</title>
        <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/tags/libros/</link>
        <description>Recent content in libros on El Baúl del programador</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>es-ES</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 13:41:11 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        <image>
            <url>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/img/bio-photo-rss.png</url>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/tags/libros/</link>
            <title>libros on El Baúl del programador</title>
            <width>144</width>
            <height>144</height>
        </image>
        <atom:link href="https://elbauldelprogramador.com/tags/libros/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Libros recomendados</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/libros-recomendados/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 13:41:11 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/libros-recomendados/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;A continuación enumero una lista de libros que he leido y que recomiendo. Iré añadiendo más conforme vaya terminando libros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si estás buscando más libros que leer, puede que te interesen las siguientes dos listas. Los libros allí mencionados no los he leido, pero los tengo pendientes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/5-libros-de-no-ficcion-que-todo-geek-deberia-leer/&#34; title=&#34;21 Libros de No-Ficción que todo Geek debería leer&#34;&gt;21 Libros de No-Ficción que todo Geek debería leer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/9-libros-que-debes-leer-para-ser-un-data-scientist-o-data-engineer/&#34; title=&#34;21 Libros Que Debes Leer Para Ser Un Data Scientist O Data Engineer&#34;&gt;21 Libros Que Debes Leer Para Ser Un Data Scientist O Data Engineer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Manual De Git Gratuito</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/manual-de-git-gratuito/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 16:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/manual-de-git-gratuito/</guid>
            <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTA&lt;/strong&gt; También puedes consultar nuestra &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/mini-tutorial-y-chuleta-de-comandos-git/&#34; title=&#34;Git: Mini Tutorial y chuleta de comandos&#34;&gt;Chuleta de comandos GIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delve into the world of Git version source control with this compact guide that discusses the features of this popular control system!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git is, without any doubt, the most popular version control system. Ironically, there are other version control systems easier to learn and to use, but, despite that, Git is the favorite option for developers, which is quite clarifying about the powerfulness of Git.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this guide, we will cover all the topics needed to know in order to use Git properly, from explaining what is it and how it differs from other tools, to its usage, covering also advanced topics and practices that can suppose an added value to the process of version controlling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this free eBook you will also receive weekly news, tips and special offers delivered to your inbox courtesy of Java Code Geeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visita la página &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/manuales-gratuitos/&#34;&gt;Manuales gratuitos&lt;/a&gt; o consulta el &lt;a href=&#34;http://elbauldelprogramador.tradepub.com/category/information-technology/1207/&#34; title=&#34;Catálogo completo de Guías gratuítas &#34;&gt;catálogo completo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guía Gratuita - Spring Data Programming Cookbook</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/libro-gratuito-spring-data-programming-cookbook/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 07:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/libro-gratuito-spring-data-programming-cookbook/</guid>
            <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delve into the world of Spring Data Programming with this compact cookbook that introduces common recipes for the Spring Data framework!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spring Data’s mission is to provide a familiar and consistent, Spring-based programming model for data access while still retaining the special traits of the underlying data store. It makes it easy to use data access technologies, relational and non-relational databases, map-reduce frameworks, and cloud-based data services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this eBook, we provide a compilation of Spring Data examples that will help you kick-start your own projects. We cover a wide range of topics, from setting up the environment and creating a basic project, to handling the various modules (e.g. JPA, MongoDB, Redis etc.). With our straightforward tutorials, you will be able to get your own projects up and running in minimum time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this free eBook you will also receive weekly news, tips and special offers delivered to your inbox courtesy of Java Code Geeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visita la página &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/manuales-gratuitos/&#34;&gt;Manuales gratuitos&lt;/a&gt; o consulta el &lt;a href=&#34;http://elbauldelprogramador.tradepub.com/category/information-technology/1207/&#34; title=&#34;Catálogo completo de Guías gratuítas &#34;&gt;catálogo completo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guía Gratuita - Python Programming Cookbook</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/libro-gratuito-python-programming-cookbook/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 08:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/libro-gratuito-python-programming-cookbook/</guid>
            <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kick-start your Python projects with these hot recipes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a widely used high-level, general-purpose, interpreted, dynamic programming language. Its design philosophy emphasizes code readability, and its syntax allows programmers to express concepts in fewer lines of code than would be possible in languages such as C++ or Java. The language provides constructs intended to enable clear programs on both a small and large scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this eBook, we provide a compilation of Python examples that will help you kick-start your own projects. We cover a wide range of topics, from multi-threaded programming to web development with Django. With our straightforward tutorials, you will be able to get your own projects up and running in minimum time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this free eBook you will also receive weekly news, tips and special offers delivered to your inbox courtesy of Web Code Geeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visita la página &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/manuales-gratuitos/&#34;&gt;Manuales gratuitos&lt;/a&gt; o consulta el &lt;a href=&#34;http://elbauldelprogramador.tradepub.com/category/information-technology/1207/&#34; title=&#34;Catálogo completo de Guías gratuítas &#34;&gt;catálogo completo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Nueva guía: 4 Key Recommendations for Cloud Integration</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-guia-4-key-recommendations-cloud-integration/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-guia-4-key-recommendations-cloud-integration/</guid>
            <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud computing is changing how businesses manage their IT assets and automate their business processes. In this new environment, IT resources are no longer housed solely on-premise and boundaries of business-to-business applications have become blurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forward-thinking organizations need to choose integration solutions that can address not only the needs that cloud computing presents today but also adapt to future challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This white paper presents the key characteristics of cloud computing, the integration challenges this deployment model introduces, four recommendations for what to look for in a solution and five key questions you should ask when considering cloud integration solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;descargar-la-guía&#34;&gt;Descargar la guía&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visita la página &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/manuales-gratuitos/&#34;&gt;Manuales gratuitos&lt;/a&gt; o consulta el &lt;a href=&#34;http://elbauldelprogramador.tradepub.com/category/information-technology/1207/&#34; title=&#34;Catálogo completo de Guías gratuítas &#34;&gt;catálogo completo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Nueva guía: 6 Steps to Securing Your Domains</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/6-steps-to-securing-your-domains/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/6-steps-to-securing-your-domains/</guid>
            <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domain hijacking is now front page news. Learn how to prevent your company’s valuable domains from being next!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Descripción de 6 Steps to Securing Your Domains&lt;/strong&gt;: When cybercriminals target your valuable domains and redirect or take them down altogether, the impact on your business is immediate and profound. Trust in your brand, business continuity and your bottom line are at risk. This informative white paper equips you with the key steps you can take to safeguard your domains. By learning about the tactics that hackers and hacktivists use to hijack domains and why it’s important to choose a hardened domain registrar, you can safeguard your domains from these dangerous and debilitating attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;descargar-6-steps-to-securing-your-domains&#34;&gt;Descargar 6 Steps to Securing Your Domains&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visita la página &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/manuales-gratuitos/&#34;&gt;Manuales gratuitos&lt;/a&gt; o consulta el &lt;a href=&#34;http://elbauldelprogramador.tradepub.com/category/information-technology/1207/&#34; title=&#34;Catálogo completo de Guías gratuítas &#34;&gt;catálogo completo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Nueva guía: 8 Steps to Building Mobile Apps Fast in the Cloud</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-guia-8-steps-to-building-mobile-apps-fast-in-the-cloud/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-guia-8-steps-to-building-mobile-apps-fast-in-the-cloud/</guid>
            <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start turning your ideas into mobile apps with the 8 Steps to Building Mobile Apps Fast in the Cloud guide, learn how to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embrace mobile design principles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create engaging apps that put customers first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make every developer a mobile one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get on the fastest path to mobile freedom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;descargar-la-guía&#34;&gt;Descargar la guía&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visita la página &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/manuales-gratuitos/&#34;&gt;Manuales gratuitos&lt;/a&gt; o consulta el &lt;a href=&#34;http://elbauldelprogramador.tradepub.com/category/information-technology/1207/&#34; title=&#34;Catálogo completo de Guías gratuítas &#34;&gt;catálogo completo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Nueva guía: A Newbies Getting Started Guide to Linux</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-guia-newbies-getting-started/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-guia-newbies-getting-started/</guid>
            <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTA&lt;/strong&gt;: Si quieres apoyar el trabajo que realizamos en &lt;em&gt;El Baúl del Programador&lt;/em&gt;, descargar alguna de estas guías es una buena forma. Para ello en el formuario de descarga &lt;strong&gt; debes indicar que trabajas en el sector relacionado con la guía que descargas, a que te dedicas etc, de lo contrario no obtendremos comisión&lt;/strong&gt; ($1.5). Si tienes un blog y quieres usar esta forma de monetización, puedes darte de alta en &lt;a id=&#34;revresponse&#34; href=&#34;http://www.revresponse.com/join.php?refbrand=bashyc-blogspot&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;RevResponse&#34;&gt;RevResponse&lt;/a&gt; y empezar a ofrecer guías de interés a tus lectores. Visita el &lt;a href=&#34;http://elbauldelprogramador.tradepub.com/category/information-technology/1207/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Catálogo completo de Guías gratuítas&#34;&gt;catálogo completo de guías.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard about Linux, the free, open-source operating system that’s been pushing up against Microsoft. It’s way cheaper, faster, safer, and has a far bigger active community than Windows, so why aren’t you on it? Don’t worry, Makeuseof.com understands. Like many things, venturing off into a completely unknown world can seem rather scary, and also be pretty difficult in the beginning. It’s while adapting to the unknown, that one needs a guiding, and caring hand. This guide will tell you all you need to know in 20 illustrated pages, helping you to take your first steps. Let your curiosity take you hostage and start discovering Linux today, with this manual as your guide! Don’t let Makeuseof.com keep you any longer, and download the Newbie’s Initiation to Linux. With this free guide you will also receive daily updates on new cool websites and programs in your email for free courtesy of MakeUseOf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Descárgala desde aqui&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; o&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visita la página &lt;a href=&#34;http://bashyc.blogspot.com/p/guias-gratuitas.html&#34;&gt;Manuales gratuitos&lt;/a&gt; para ver las guías disponibles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Nueva Guía: Big Security for Big Data</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-guia-big-security-for-big-data/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-guia-big-security-for-big-data/</guid>
            <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The multitude of devices, users, and generated traffic all combine to create a proliferation of data that is being created with incredible volume, velocity, and variety. Organizations need a way to protect, utilize, and gain real-time insight from “big data.” This intelligence is not only valuable to businesses and consumers, but also to hackers. Robust information marketplaces have arisen for hackers to sell credit card information, account usernames, passwords, national secrets (WikiLeaks), as well as intellectual property. In order to meet the current security problems faced by organizations, a new paradigm shift needs to occur. Businesses need the ability to secure data, collect it, and aggregate into an intelligent format, so that real-time alerting and reporting can take place. So, how do we get started?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;referencias&#34;&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visita la página &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/manuales-gratuitos/&#34;&gt;Manuales gratuitos&lt;/a&gt; o consulta el &lt;a href=&#34;http://elbauldelprogramador.tradepub.com/category/information-technology/1207/&#34; title=&#34;Catálogo completo de Guías gratuítas &#34;&gt;catálogo completo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Nueva guía: FAQ Guide: Windows 7 Migrations Are the Time to Lockdown PCs</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-guia-faq-guide-windows-7/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-guia-faq-guide-windows-7/</guid>
            <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This FAQ Guide for enterprise IT management explains why Windows 7 migrations are prompting organizations to re-assess their approach to securing and managing desktops. Users who are “Administrators” on their endpoints do not need admin rights to accomplish daily tasks - and having free reign on software installation and endpoint based operations often leads to malware and data breaches that are costly to your company’s reputation and bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://elbauldelprogramador.tradepub.com/c/pubRD.mpl?sr=oc&amp;amp;_t=oc:&amp;amp;pc;=w_view10/prgm.cgi&#34;&gt;Descárgala desde aqui&lt;/a&gt; o
Visita la página &lt;a href=&#34;http://bashyc.blogspot.com/p/guias-gratuitas.html&#34;&gt;Manuales gratuitos&lt;/a&gt; para ver las guías disponibles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Nueva guía: History of cryptography</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/history-of-cryptography/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/history-of-cryptography/</guid>
            <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An easy to understand history of cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Descripción de History of Cryptography&lt;/strong&gt;: This white paper presents a brief history of cryptography and how encryption-related technologies have evolved and will continue to evolve as well as the measures Internet users should consider when implementing modern encryptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryptography is an ancient science, but, with the rise of the information age, computers have brought it to a whole new level. Online privacy and security both depend on encryption, and maintaining a strong standard is more important than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryptography is one of the oldest fields of technical study we can find records of, going back at least 4 000 years. Ciphering has always been considered vital for diplomatic and military secrecy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;descargar&#34;&gt;Descargar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visita la página &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/manuales-gratuitos/&#34;&gt;Manuales gratuitos&lt;/a&gt; o consulta el &lt;a href=&#34;http://elbauldelprogramador.tradepub.com/category/information-technology/1207/&#34; title=&#34;Catálogo completo de Guías gratuítas &#34;&gt;catálogo completo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Nueva guía: How the internet works</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-guia-how-internet-works/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-guia-how-internet-works/</guid>
            <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web’s place in our daily lives is undeniable. We can now access the Internet from our home computers, office, laptops and our phones. But even with this close intimacy many people still aren’t entirely sure what the Internet is and how it really works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aim to change that with this PDF guide, “How The Internet Works.” This guide, by Taty Sena, explores the hardware, software and organizations that power the modern Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll learn about everything from the history of the Internet to the organizations that make it possible today. You probably use the Internet every day, so educate yourself. You don’t need to know how the Internet works to use it, of course, but that doesn’t mean anyone can’t benefit from a quick overview:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The history of the web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How information is transferred&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What DNS servers do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The languages of the web, including HTML, java and more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current Internet trends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How the web changed the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also with this free guide you will also receive daily updates on new cool websites and programs in your email for free courtesy of MakeUseOf.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://elbauldelprogramador.tradepub.com/free/w_make28/prgm.cgi&#34;&gt;Descárgala desde aqui&lt;/a&gt; o
Visita la página &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/manuales-gratuitos/&#34;&gt;Manuales gratuitos&lt;/a&gt; para ver las guías disponibles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Nueva guía: Mac OS X Lion: The Ultimate Guide</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-guia-mac-os-x-lion-ultimate-guide/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-guia-mac-os-x-lion-ultimate-guide/</guid>
            <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Description: **Deliberate or not, calling this version of OS X the king of the big cats brings along some big connotations. This is it. This is the pinnacle of OS. What could possibly come after Lion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does this ultimate version of Mac OS X bring to the table? What makes it worth using? What makes this operating system the king of cats? Download now to find out. Also with this free guide you will also receive daily updates on new cool websites and programs in your email for free courtesy of MakeUseOf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bashyc-blogspot.tradepub.com/c/pubRD.mpl?sr=oc&amp;amp;_t=oc:&amp;amp;qf=w_make45&#34;&gt;Descárgala desde aqui&lt;/a&gt; o
Visita la página &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/manuales-gratuitos/&#34;&gt;Manuales gratuitos&lt;/a&gt; para ver las guías disponibles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Nueva Guía: The Essentials of Information Security Kit</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-gua-the-essentials-of-information-security-kit/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 08:14:31 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/nueva-gua-the-essentials-of-information-security-kit/</guid>
            <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download this kit to learn everything you need to know about Information Security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Essentials of Information Security brings together the latest in information, coverage of important developments, and expert commentary to help with your Information Security related decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following kit contents will help you get the most out of your Information Security research:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PC Security Handbook - 2nd Edition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigating the Threat Landscape: A Practical Guide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top Tips for Securing Big Data Environments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encryption as an Enterprise Strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visita la página &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/manuales-gratuitos/&#34;&gt;Manuales gratuitos&lt;/a&gt; o consulta el &lt;a href=&#34;http://elbauldelprogramador.tradepub.com/category/information-technology/1207/&#34; title=&#34;Catálogo completo de Guías gratuítas &#34;&gt;catálogo completo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>21 Libros Que Debes Leer Para Ser Un Data Scientist O Data Engineer</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/9-libros-que-debes-leer-para-ser-un-data-scientist-o-data-engineer/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 20:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/9-libros-que-debes-leer-para-ser-un-data-scientist-o-data-engineer/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Tras mucho buscar, al fin he conseguido recopilar una lista de libros que todo &lt;em&gt;Científico de Datos&lt;/em&gt; o &lt;em&gt;Ingeniero de Datos&lt;/em&gt; debería tener en su
biblioteca personal. Sin más dilaciones, he aquí la lista (La descrición de los libros ha sido cogida de Amazon)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;para-data-scientist&#34;&gt;Para Data Scientist&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;figure&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;/img/ml/pythonmachinelearning.jpg&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;img
      on=&amp;quot;tap:lightbox1&amp;quot;
      role=&amp;quot;button&amp;quot;
      tabindex=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;
      layout=&amp;quot;responsive&amp;quot;
      src=&amp;quot;/img/ml/pythonmachinelearning.jpg&amp;quot;
      alt=&amp;quot;Python Machine Learning book&amp;quot;
      title=&amp;quot;Python Machine Learning book&amp;quot;
      sizes=&amp;quot;(min-width: 380px) 380px, 100vw&amp;quot;
      width=&amp;quot;380&amp;quot;
      height=&amp;quot;468&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/img&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;



&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Unlock deeper insights into Machine Leaning with this vital guide to cutting-edge predictive analytics. Leverage Python&#39;s most powerful open-source libraries for deep learning, data wrangling, and data visualization&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;tags&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://amzn.to/2se4MjS&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Ver en Amazon&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;para-data-engineer&#34;&gt;Para Data Engineer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;sobre-big-data&#34;&gt;Sobre Big Data&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;más-libros&#34;&gt;Más libros&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si te interesan los libros &lt;em&gt;geek&lt;/em&gt;, visita nuestra recopilación &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/5-libros-de-no-ficcion-que-todo-geek-deberia-leer/&#34;&gt;16 Libros de No-Ficción que todo Geek debería leer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;referencias&#34;&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.analyticsvidhya.com&#34;&gt;Analyticsvidhya.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>21 Libros de No-Ficción que todo Geek debería leer</title>
            <link>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/5-libros-de-no-ficcion-que-todo-geek-deberia-leer/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 16:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://elbauldelprogramador.com/5-libros-de-no-ficcion-que-todo-geek-deberia-leer/</guid>
            <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;aportaciones-de-los-lectores&#34;&gt;Aportaciones de los lectores&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A continuación una lista de libros que han recomendado los lectores del blog en los comentarios. Gracias a todos!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusión&#34;&gt;Conclusión&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estos libros son algunos de los mejores que puedes leer si estás interesado en aprender más sobre tecnología de consumo. Muchos de ellos se focalizan en ángulos o tópicos específicos, pero no es fácil ver cómo las lecciones que se encuentran en ellos aplican a otras áreas de interés de geeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¿Qué piensas? ¿Has leído un libro no-ficción sobre tecnología que creas que debería estar en el &lt;em&gt;canon del geek&lt;/em&gt;? Háznoslo saber en los comentarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuente: &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;makeuseof&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;más-libros&#34;&gt;Más libros&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Echa un vistazo a nuestra lista de &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/9-libros-que-debes-leer-para-ser-un-data-scientist-o-data-engineer/&#34;&gt;libros que todo Data Scientist y Data Engineer debería leer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
